<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>San Antonio Real Estate Podcast with Cathy Naiser</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Cathy Naiser, Realtor Powered X The Castillo Group - your professional San Antonio Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Cathy Naiser</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2022-02-22 15:48:44 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Cathy Naiser</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>cathy@mysanantoniomove.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Cathy Naiser</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Antonio Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Cathy Naiser, Realtor Powered X The Castillo Group - your professional San Antonio Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Naiser Group Is Now Powered by TCG</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-naiser-group-is-now-powered-by-tcg.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Announcement</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2022-02-21 12:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’ve combined forces with TCG to better serve all of San Antonio.

I’m very excited to make a huge announcement. After serving the San Antonio real estate community for the last 16 years, I’ve decided to take my business to a new level. The Cathy Naiser Group has partnered with one of the top teams in San Antonio and the entire United States, The Castillo Group, to provide more resources for our clients and the educator community. I’m excited to tell you more about this partnership in the coming days. 

We’re going to give every transaction an efficient and successful landing as we combine forces to offer the best possible experience for our buyers and sellers. We can’t wait to help each other grow and become one big family.

If you have any questions about our partnership, your home sale, or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’ve combined forces with TCG to better serve all of San Antonio.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’ve combined forces with TCG to better serve all of San Antonio.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>My Wishes for You This Holiday Season</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/my-wishes-for-you-this-holiday-season.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2021-12-17 10:48:53 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

                       Here are my wishes for you during this wonderful holiday season.

I have a few wishes for you this holiday season:

I wish you time to reflect. Reflect on what’s important to you and how you can nurture that in your life. Reflect on what you’re grateful for and what you’ve learned.

I wish you time to relax. These last couple of years have been hard, so relax and heal from the losses, drama, and pain.

I wish you time for fun. We haven’t had nearly enough of it, so really embrace having fun during the holidays.

“Reflect on what’s important to you and how you can nurture that in your life.”

I wish you time to dream. Dream about what can be, where you want to go, or what you want your life to look like someday. Walt Disney created his vision of Disneyland long before it existed. What is your legacy?

I wish you time to plan. How are you going to march towards that legacy every day?

I wish you time to remember and be in the moment. The best “someday” is the day we have right now.

We all come from different spiritual traditions and backgrounds, but I’m sure we all believe in love and the power of good in the world. In my tradition, we say merry Christmas. Whatever your holiday is, I wish you the best holiday and a very happy new year.

If you have any questions, feel free to call or email me. I would love to hear from you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are my wishes for you during this wonderful holiday season.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are my wishes for you during this wonderful holiday season.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tracking Our Changing Interest Rates</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tracking-our-changing-interest-rates.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2021-11-08 10:46:35 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

                                                           Here’s what our changing interest rates mean for buyers and sellers.

Today I’m joined by guest speaker Holden Hamilton, one of my favorite loan officers from Gold Financial, who is here to tell us what has happened over the last couple of years in terms of interest rates.

Back in May of 2020, though everyone started to feel the repercussions of COVID in terms of jobs, those of us in real estate were very blessed to be in the housing industry during that rough time. The Federal Reserve started purchasing mortgage-backed securities and bonds at nearly $120 million a month. Market watchers predicted the tapering of bonds per FED announcements late September 2021. With this news the market reacted with an increase in interest rates over the past few weeks. The official announcement came early November and will begin to actually taper December of 2021. That had the effect of hiking up interest rates, along with inflation, unemployment, and other miscellaneous factors.

For reference, here are some key statistics to note: One year ago your interest rate on a $300,000 home would have been 2.75%, which would put you at $1,163 a month in principle and interest. A month ago, the rate was 3.125%, which would have put you at a $1,220 monthly payment. Today the rate is 3.375%, which is a $1,259 monthly payment. That’s a $96 difference!

As economists and leaders in our industry, we look at where it’s most beneficial to invest that money, be it in the real estate market or the stock market. Suppose you took that $96 you would have saved if you bought a year ago and put it in the stock market at an average rate of about 10% per year—if you would have done that over the life of your 30-year loan, it would amount to $218,000 from just a $96 monthly investment. 

“If you’re buying or selling a home this year, you could be impacted by rising interest rates.”

You also have to look at appreciation. Homes have appreciated at about a rate of 7.83% over the last three years. If you bought a $300,000 home two or three years ago, your home would be worth around $376,000 today. That’s a huge difference!

So what does this all mean? It means that now is not the time to wait; you don’t want to get to a point where homes are so expensive that you can’t buy what you want. You also don’t want to buy it at an increased interest rate; ideally, you’d retain that money and invest it elsewhere, letting it do the work for you.

If you think that it’s best to wait until the spring or summer of next year to buy, understand that interest rates may be even higher then. Though it may be a little bit of a challenge to sell during the holidays, many buyers still purchase homes during this time because it’s very nostalgic to buy a home for Christmas.

Ultimately, if you’re buying or selling a home this year, you could be impacted by rising interest rates. Give us a call or send an email today. Let’s talk through the benefits of acting now as opposed to waiting. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Interest rates are rising.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Interest rates are rising.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A List of Resources You Should Take Advantage Of</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-list-of-resources-you-should-take-advantage-of.html</link>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2021-04-01 17:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Whether you&rsquo;re buying or selling a home, here&rsquo;s how we can help.

&nbsp;

We at the Naiser Real Estate Group have so many ways to help people, whether they’re buying, selling, or doing neither. Today I’ll outline just a few of the ways we can assist you:


  If you’re not selling your home, you may want to think about refinancing it. If you haven’t already, you could refinance your home with a Keller Mortgage Zero Plus loan, which would save you thousands of dollars on fees and interest. Buyers can also save thousands using this loan; call us first, though, because there may be other programs that can help you as well.
  With home prices and appreciation on the rise, your home may actually be underinsured. To get custom quotes from multiple insurance companies, visit www.KellerCovered.com. If you mention me as your agent, you can get a discount. 
  You can also watch prices in your neighborhood and the surrounding areas by using our Monthly Neighborhood Snapshot. If you’re not already receiving those, reach out to us and we’d happily add you to our contact list.
  To make your next home search easier, download my app on your phone, which lets you search by neighborhood, school, and ZIP code.
  If you’re looking to buy a home before you sell your current one, our Buy Before You Sell Plan is exactly what you need. Reach out to us for more details!
  You could get instant cash offers for your home without showings or commission when you work with me through Keller Offers. Keller Offers is an iBuyer program like OpenDoor and Zillow, except we won’t charge you a commission.
  Use our upsize and downsize programs to sell your home, buy a new or pre-owned home, or even build one. These programs often beat the move-up programs that builders provide.
  Call us to learn about our Win the House Program. It’s very competitive for buyers in the market, but luckily this special program will help you win the house you desire. 


These are just a few of the ways we serve people and help them move forward in their lives. No matter if you’re thinking about buying a home, selling a home, or something else, consider us as your real estate resource. Don’t hesitate to reach out! We’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Whether you’re buying or selling a home, here’s how we can help.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Whether you’re buying or selling a home, here’s how we can help.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ways to Make 2021 Better</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/ways-to-make-2021-better.html</link>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2021-02-11 09:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We want to help you make 2021 better than 2020. Here&rsquo;s how we&rsquo;re doing it.

&nbsp;

Do you want 2021 to be way better than 2020? We can help make that happen, whether or not you’re interested in buying or selling a home. We decided to do a few unique things for our friends and clients that we’ve never done before. This year, we’ll be hosting four different webinars to start, and you can find out all the information about them by visiting CathysWebinars.com. 

Simply follow the links below to register for the webinars that appeal to you. Here’s a quick rundown of each one:

Balance and Fun in 2021. We feel balance and fun are getting left by the wayside during the pandemic, so having it in our lives right now means you need to be intentional about it. We’ll be using the book “The 12-Week Year” and a planning tool to show you strategies to ensure you get balance and fun back into your life.

Get the Home You Really Want. This one is all about buying and selling a home. This will cover programs that will help you buy and/or sell. 

Get the Most Money for Your Home Sale: Prepare for the Home Inspection. For this webinar, I’ll be partnering with a home inspector to prepare sellers for certain things before they ever list their house. A seller may get many offers immediately, but after the inspection, the buyer could back out because it yielded surprising results. 

10 Things San Antonio Area Landlords Need to Know in 2021. This webinar is great for landlords and those who want to become landlords. Jason and Pete from the Bridgeman Properties Group will join me to discuss evictions, COVID-19 restrictions, the sales market, the rental market, and more.

You can attend these webinars or watch the video replays later if you miss them. These live webinars are completely free, and we’ll have question and answer sessions at the end.

If you have questions about these webinars or anything real estate-related, call or email us. We hope to speak with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We want to help you make 2021 better than 2020. Here’s how we’re doing it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We want to help you make 2021 better than 2020. Here’s how we’re doing it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our New Buy Before You Sell Program</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-new-buy-before-you-sell-program.html</link>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2021-01-12 08:31:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

There&rsquo;s a way for you to buy a new home before you sell.

&nbsp;

For years, we’ve helped people in Bexar and the surrounding counties sell their homes and buy other homes. That’s a challenge for many because they need to sell their home first, but can’t seem to buy a home first. Now, however, we have our Buy Before You Sell plan that our sellers love.

In the past, we used to help people sell and buy using contingent offers, meaning they would go find a house before their own sold and place an offer on it that was contingent on the sale of their current home. 

That used to work, but for a while now, our market has been very hot, and sellers have had plenty of buyers to choose from. Buyers with contingent offers haven’t been getting theirs accepted very much at all.

So what happens then? Well, sellers have to get their homes ready, put them on the market, have showings, get it under contract, and before it closes, move somewhere temporarily. Then they go find another home and use the funds from their current sale to buy it.

Now we have the option to help sellers buy a home before they sell their current one. First, our clients are qualified through our partner company, which will likely end up financing their home. Once they’re qualified, we help them find a home and write a competitive offer on it. 

Our partner company buys the house with a cash offer (which often wins in multiple-offer situations), and our clients are able to move into that house while they get their own house fixed up, listed to the market, and sold. When their house closes, they can immediately buy the home back from our partner company. There is a 1.9% fee if they don’t finance with our partner company and 1.4% if they do. Clients will also have to pay rent for the time they lived in the house before they bought it—but they’d have to pay rent if they moved somewhere temporarily, too.

The convenience of this program is that you wouldn’t have to move twice and you have the opportunity to move out of your current home while you prep it for the market. That’s huge for a lot of people.

“The convenience of this program is that you wouldn’t have to move twice.”

Whether you’re looking to sell the traditional way or you’re interested in our Buy Before You Sell plan, don’t hesitate to reach out to us for your real estate needs. We have many programs that can work to your benefit.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There’s a way for you to buy a new home before you sell.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There’s a way for you to buy a new home before you sell.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Do Real Estate Deals Fall Apart?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-do-real-estate-deals-fall-apart.html</link>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2020-11-13 08:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Ever wonder why contracts fall through and houses go back on the market? Today we’re going to through some of the most common reasons why this situation occurs and how we can help you avoid this.

If a buyer is moving too fast, for example, and they throw in an offer just to win the house, they can sometimes have buyer’s remorse and terminate the contract. That’s a difficult situation for everyone involved. With our listings, we have several things in place to make sure the buyer takes a little bit of time to think about their offer before it’s presented. We also research the buyer before we go under contract with them.

Because we’ve seen so many houses throughout the years, we are able to really help our buyers evaluate properties before ever making an offer. We explain the market, the pros and cons of the house, and then advise on how to go forward. Not all agents do that.

“Our experience really helps our clients.”

Another reason deals fall apart stems from appraisal issues. In this hot seller’s market, more and more homes are selling over list price. The problem with this is that they don’t always appraise, which can create a problematic situation. When we meet with buyers and sellers, we really emphasize and discuss the expectations around the appraisal so that if it does come in low, our clients already know the best course to follow. Our experience really helps our clients.

Buying and selling a home is one of the largest financial transactions of your life and it can become emotional and stressful. We hold in-depth consultations before even beginning the process so we can explain the ups and downs of the journey so they totally understand what’s happening and are prepared. With as many clients as we’ve helped throughout the years, we can answer any questions a client may have.

We also work with the agent on the other side of the transition to make sure all expectations are clear, timelines are clear, and everyone is on the same page. We “bulletproof” the transaction as much as we can prior to even starting it.

Even with all the preparation in the world, some contracts will still fall through. When they do, we are ready and equipped with a positive plan to move forward so our clients still win the day in their home buying or selling journey.

If you have any questions for me about this topic or anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s how we help prevent our clients’ deals from falling apart.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s how we help prevent our clients’ deals from falling apart.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can Buyers Win a Bidding War?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-buyers-win-a-bidding-war.html</link>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2020-11-12 08:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I’ve been hearing of buyers and sellers who don’t even want to enter the market because they’re afraid of the competition that comes with the frequent bidding wars we see in our market. Today I’m here to say that you don’t have to be afraid of bidding wars, and there are ways you can win them. Occasionally one of our buyers will lose a bidding war to a cash buyer, but most of the time, they come out on top. Here are my tips to help you find success in our competitive market:

1. Work with an experienced agent who can offer a proven strategy. 

2. Make a good offer. In this market, you should offer full price or more; in most bidding wars that I’m seeing, homes are selling between $10,000 and $20,000 over list price.

3. Shorten your timelines. Having shorter timelines in your contract can make a seller very happy and more likely to accept your offer over others who haven’t shortened theirs.

4. Ask the seller for as few closing costs as possible. Sometimes buyers ask the sellers to pay some of their closing costs, but sellers have their own, as well. Buyers who ask too much in this regard rarely win bidding wars. If you need closing costs assistance, then apply for a down payment assistance program, or get gift funds from family.

“If you can afford to pay your closing costs, then I encourage you to go in guns blazing with an offer that no one can beat.”

5. Write a personal letter to go with your offer. Include a picture of you and your family (as well as any pets) and let the seller know why their house is perfect for your family. Sellers love these kinds of letters, and sometimes they can even make the difference between getting accepted or rejected.

6. Offer to pay some of the seller’s fees. If you make an offer above full price but the house doesn’t appraise, the seller has to come down some. The seller will be happier with your offer in that scenario because you’ll be paying some of their fees, allowing them to net more.

7. Send the sellers a comparative net sheet of all their offers. Some sellers don’t even know what the offer is going to net them because their agent doesn’t know how to do net sheets (or doesn’t do them well). Have your agent send over a net sheet that shows them how much your offer will net them now as well as what it would net if their home didn’t appraise.

These tips will help you give your offer a competitive edge in this market. If you’re trying to avoid a bidding war, look at houses that have been on the market for 10 to 14 days; they could still end up with multiple offers, but it’s not likely to get out of hand. If you can afford to pay your closing costs, then I encourage you to go in guns blazing with an offer that no one can beat.

If we can help you come up with a strategy based on your situation, reach out to us. We love working with buyers and sellers, and we’d be happy to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Use these seven tips to help you win the home during a bidding war.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Use these seven tips to help you win the home during a bidding war.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: Which 5 Home Improvements Offer a Great Return?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-which-5-home-improvements-offer-a-great-return.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2020-10-26 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Recently, I’ve helped a number of people sell their homes, and one lady in particular needed some painting and landscaping work done on her property. She consulted with us and followed our instructions for some simple updates to make around her home. After a staging consultation, we listed the home and received multiple offers on it after just four days, which drove the price up as high as it could go. If you want to follow in this seller’s footsteps and sell quickly for above asking price, keep these specific home improvements in mind: 

1. Neutralize the color palette. Light gray is a very popular color these days, but beige or even “greige” are also solid choices that buyers seem to love. Just make sure that the gray you pick doesn’t appear as a light blue in your home’s lighting. 

2. Update your curb appeal. Your front door is very important as far as first impressions go, so restain or repaint it if it looks dated. If it’s noticeably worn or has busted hardware, replacing it will definitely be worth your money. Also, power washing the driveway and sidewalks makes everything seem fresher, as does adding new plants to your flower bed. Mulch is the amazing forgiver of all home gardening sins, so be sure to add a fresh layer in there, too. Don’t forget to keep your shrubs and trees trimmed so that there are no branches hanging down precariously over the roof. 

“Mulch is the amazing forgiver of all home gardening sins, so be sure to add a fresh layer in your flower bed.”

3. Update your flooring. Waterproof vinyl-plank “wood” flooring is quite popular right now because it’s much easier to install (and uninstall) than ceramic tile and it looks sleek. If you have older carpets, it’s time to replace them. If you’re worrying about buyers not liking the new carpet you choose, don’t—even if your buyer ends up replacing it later, your home will always show 10x better with brand-new carpets, and that’s what counts. You’ll also want to clean the grout on your tile floors (if you need help with this, I have an amazing vendor who specializes in making grout look fresh). 

4. Update your kitchen. This is probably the most important room in your whole house, so update it as much as you can. That could mean adding some new fixtures or staining or repainting the cabinets a nice clean white or grayish color. Of course, granite or quartz countertops always help as well. 

5. Let in as much natural light as you can. Open things up and let the sunshine brighten every space in your home. Clean the blinds, clean the windows, and remove solar screens if you have them. Before listing, it might behoove you to invest in some “daylight” light bulbs—they really provide a certain glow that buyers respond well to. 

Hopefully you found this list to be helpful. Don’t hesitate to reach out by phone or email if you want some specialized information for your particular selling needs; we’d be more than happy to check out your home and offer some tips and tricks. In the meantime, we’re always here to answer any questions you may have. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are the five home improvements that offer the best bang for your buck.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are the five home improvements that offer the best bang for your buck.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: Why Is It a “Magical” Time for Our Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-why-is-it-a-magical-time-for-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2020-08-25 16:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

It’s a magical time in the San Antonio real estate market. First, let me say that I hope you are all safe and healthy. 

In any real estate market, homes can sell very quickly if marketed well and priced correctly. In the market we’re in right now, this is even more true due to a lack of inventory. 

“We’re helping clients sell in an average of just 14 days.”

We have a process that keeps our buyers and sellers as safe as possible. We have a pricing strategy that helps homes sell very quickly (in an average of just 14 days) and for top dollar. The average days on market for all homes in San Antonio is currently over 60. 

At the same time, we can help buyers win by helping them tailor their offer to a seller’s needs. Whatever your real estate dreams are, we can help you achieve them.

If you have any questions about what buying or selling a home looks like today or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re ready to help homeowners take full advantage of market conditions.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re ready to help homeowners take full advantage of market conditions.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Win Amazing Prizes From Our 4th of July Giveaway</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/win-amazing-prizes-from-our-4th-of-july-giveaway.html</link>
        
          <category>Community</category>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2020-06-24 16:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

There are so many serious things going on in the world, but today we wanted to take some time to have fun and do something positive. That’s why the Naiser Real Estate Group is partnering with the Hamilton Group of Gold Financial Mortgage to present a Fourth of July giveaway.

Let me tell you, these prizes are amazing! Here’s what you could win: 


  A four-burner Royal Gourmet blacktop grill
  A 45-gallon Yeti Tundra cooler
  The Yeti lunch combo, including a lunch bag and two 30-ounce Yeti tumblers


To enter, all you need to do is call our office at 737-222-7295 on July 1 between 10 a.m. and 3 p.m. and talk to us. If you go to voicemail, be sure to leave a message and we’ll call you back ASAP—we must speak with you to enter. When you call, we’ll ask you to confirm your contact information so that we know where to deliver your prize should you win.

“If you refer us to someone interested in buying or selling a home, you’ll be entered into the drawing twice.”

Additionally, if you’re aware of anyone who wants to buy or sell a home within the next 12 months, let us know. If you refer someone, you’ll be entered into the drawing twice!

When the contest is over later that day, we’ll use a randomizer to pick the winners. The prizes will be delivered July 2 so you’ll be able to use them for the Fourth of July holiday.

Be sure to mark your calendars! In the meantime, if you have any questions about buying and selling real estate, don’t hesitate to contact us. We’d love to be  your resource.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This July, we’re giving away some amazing prizes that will come in handy for the Fourth of July holiday.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This July, we’re giving away some amazing prizes that will come in handy for the Fourth of July holiday.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Do You Like to Look at Houses on the Internet?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/do-you-like-to-look-at-houses-on-the-internet.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-29 09:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you like to spend time looking online at the latest real estate statistics and browsing homes for sale, then you’re going to love this new app.

If you haven’t heard yet, the new Keller Williams app just launched and it’s fantastic. 

To download it, all you have to do is text “KW15TB9I” (the last digit is a capital I and not a #1) to 87778.

You’ll get a link sent to you and you can download the app right on your phone by clicking the aforementioned link.

“We don’t sell insurance, but our app allows you to compare the best quotes.”

Like most real estate apps, this app allows you to narrow down your home search. In addition to searching by area and price range, you can search by school, school district, or neighborhood. No other app has something like this. 

Down at the bottom of the app, if you click the icon that says “more,” you can do several things. You can add a co-buyer, apply for a mortgage with Keller Mortgage, or get instant homeowners insurance quotes from multiple companies with Keller Covered. We don’t sell insurance, but our app allows you to compare insurance companies and even get an extra discount.

With this app, you can also call, email, or text me with any questions right from the app. This is one of the most cutting-edge real estate tools out there.

If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The brand-new Keller Williams app has everything homebuyers need.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The brand-new Keller Williams app has everything homebuyers need.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Our Market Is Not Like the One We Saw Back in 2008</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-our-market-is-not-like-the-one-we-saw-back-in-2008.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-01 12:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Considering everything that’s happening with the COVID-19 pandemic, now is an uncertain time in the world, but the real estate market is moving ahead. To be clear, this market is not like the one we saw back in 2008 that led to the Great Recession, and there are several reasons why. 

1. Mortgage standards aren’t the same. In 2008, mortgage standards were very loose. Anyone could get a loan. You could have bad credit, you did not have to prove your income and appraisals were super high. After the market crashed, the lesson was learned, and mortgage standards were tightened. Now you need good credit and solid, provable income, and appraisals aren’t coming in high anymore. 

2. Prices are in control. Housing prices have been rising steadily in San Antonio and across the nation but not at the rate that they were in 2008. Back then, prices were skyrocketing and investors from California were swooping in and buying entire neighborhoods sight unseen because they could get them cheaply (even though they were so expensive for regular consumers).

3. 2008 had too much inventory. In other words, there were too many houses on the market, but that’s not the case today. We’ve been pretty consistent inventory-wise. Each month we may have about 7,500 houses for sale, but only about 2,500 to 3,500 are selling, and those numbers stay the same even as we enter April 2020. 

“The point is, people are still buying and selling.”

4. People have more equity in their homes now. In 2008, many people were buying homes with crazy loans and found themselves upside down on their mortgages. When those people couldn’t afford to sell, they went into foreclosure, which exacerbated the problem. People are being wiser with their home purchases, though, and that’s resulted in a general increase in equity. 

5. Sales continue. Even with the stay-at-home order in place, the week prior to the recording of this video saw the following stats:


  1,501 new listings
  969 houses went under contract
  758 houses sold


Even stranger, in the 24 hours prior to this video, there were 364 new listings and 220 homes that went under contract. 

The point is, people are still buying and selling. We’ve attended meetings, coordinated home equity assessments, and held home buying appointments all on virtual platforms. If you want to buy now, we can grant you a virtual showing and spotlight every inch of a property. We also offer 24-hour open houses featuring detailed walk-throughs. There’s no sense in waiting a few weeks—the market is taking off now. 

If you have questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m here to help, and I hope you and your family are staying safe during this time. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our current market isn’t like the one we saw in 2008. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our current market isn’t like the one we saw in 2008. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Best Time of Year for San Antonio Real Estate?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-the-best-time-of-year-for-san-antonio-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-25 14:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Cathy+Naiser/The+Best+Time+to+Buy+or+Sell+in+San+Antonio.mp4</guid>
        <description>

People often ask me, “What is the best time of year to buy or sell a home in San Antonio?” 

Since our market is very steady, I find that the ratio between houses on the market and houses being purchased to be fairly consistent throughout the year.

“I’m seeing buyers become a little more picky.”

In the fall and winter, there are fewer houses on the market and fewer buyers buying. This means buyers and sellers have less competition. In the spring and summer, there are more houses on the market and more competition. 

No matter what time of year that you decide to list or buy, you will do the best when you have a great strategy. Right now, interest rates are still low and I have ways to save you money on closing costs– if you’re a buyer. For sellers, I’m seeing buyers become a little more picky. Updated homes are doing very well, while those that aren’t should have a different selling strategy.

Meeting with a great real estate agent, like me, can let you know exactly what to do to prepare your home for the market. Remember that I can also provide an instant cash offer. This can help if you want to sell without showings and you want a flexible closing date.

Ultimately, the best time to buy or sell is when the time is right for you. If anytime in 2020 is the right time for you, feel free to reach out to me via phone or email today. I look forward to hearing from you. 

Now Setting Appointments for Spring Break!

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Cathy+Naiser/The+Best+Time+to+Buy+or+Sell+in+San+Antonio.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Cathy+Naiser/The+Best+Time+to+Buy+or+Sell+in+San+Antonio.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is there a “best time” to buy or sell a home in San Antonio? Here’s my expert opinion.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is there a “best time” to buy or sell a home in San Antonio? Here’s my expert opinion.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Been Getting Cash Offers for Your Home in the Mail?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/have-you-been-getting-cash-offers-for-your-home-in-the-mail.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Cathy Naiser</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-28 11:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I’m devoting today’s message to making sense of those home offers you’ve likely been receiving in the mail. There are different types of offers sent out by different types of interested parties. For example, there are wholesalers, investor flippers, and iBuyers. Our focus will be on iBuyers, or institutional buyers, which have become so prevalent in today’s market. 

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure:

0:23—Explaining the marketing extravaganza of mail offers 

1:07—Wholesalers 

1:44—Investor flippers

2:25—Overview of iBuyers (the difference between Keller Offers and popular sites like Zillow)

3:21—How the institutional buyers compare to the average investor flipper

4:07—iBuyer fees 

5:06—Benefits of an iBuyer, breakdown of the Keller Offers program 

6:27—Wrapping things up 

If you know anyone who’s considering selling a home, have them call me. I’m able to give them options and great representation. As always, thanks for watching, and reach out to me via phone or email if you have any questions. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re considering selling to an iBuyer, here’s what you should know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Cathy Naiser</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re considering selling to an iBuyer, here’s what you should know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Antonio, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Cathy Naiser</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Cathy Naiser</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Cathy Naiser, Realtor Powered X The Castillo Group - your professional San Antonio Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
